<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
	<id>com.github.blackhole89.notekit</id>
	<metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
	<project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
	<name>NoteKit</name>
	<launchable type="desktop-id">com.github.blackhole89.notekit.desktop</launchable>
	<summary>A GTK3 hierarchical markdown notetaking application with tablet support</summary>
	<description>
		<p>
			This program is a structured notetaking application based on GTK+ 3.
			Write your notes in instantly-formatted Markdown, organise them in a
			tree of folders that can be instantly navigated from within the
			program, and add hand-drawn notes by mouse, touchscreen or
			digitiser.
		</p>
		<p>
			<em>Why?</em>
		</p>
		<p>
			I figured it would be nice to have a free-software,
			platform-independent OneNote. While there is a remarkable number of
			free (speech or beer) notetaking applications out there, to my best
			knowledge, none of them simultaneously check the following boxes:
		</p>
		<ul>
			<li>note organisation</li>
			<li>text as a first-class object</li>
			<li>formatting</li>
			<li>simple, standard on-disk format</li>
			<li>tablet input</li>
		</ul>
		<p>
			<em>Usage notes</em>
		</p>
		<p>
			Note management
		</p>
		<ul>
			<li>To create a new note, doubleclick a "+" node in the tree view
				and enter a name.</li>
			<li>To create a new folder, doubleclick a "+" node in the tree view
				and enter a name ending in "/", e.g. new "folder/".</li>
			<li>Notes will be sorted alphabetically.</li>
			<li>You can move notes and whole folders between folders by dragging
				and dropping.</li>
			<li>Files are saved automatically when the window is closed, when a
				different file is opened, and after a timeout when no user
				action is performed.</li>
		</ul>
		<p>
			Markdown
		</p>
		<ul>
			<li>Some markdown features are unsupported as a stylistic choice or
				because of parser limitations. If you are feeling adventurous,
				you can adjust the markdown parser by editing the GtkSourceView
				language definition in "sourceview/markdown.lang".</li>
			<li>Add LaTeX math using single "$" signs, e.g. "$\int x dx$".</li>
			<li>Some markdown will be hidden ("rendered") unless your cursor is
				next to it.</li>
		</ul>
		<p>
			Note management
		</p>
		<ul>
			<li>Drawings can currently only be deleted whole. (This will be
				fixed eventually.)</li>
			<li>To edit the default colour palette, right-click any of the
				colour buttons on the right-hand toolbar.</li>
			<li>Due to present limitations, drawing clears the undo stack.</li>
			<li>When copypasting text into other applications, drawings will be
				automatically converted into data URL PNGs.</li>
		</ul>
		<p>
			Note management
		</p>
		<ul>
			<li>
				The program loads a custom Gtk+ stylesheet found in
				"data/stylesheet.css". Clear it if parts of the UI look wonky.
			</li>
			<li>If something unexpected happens, it is often useful to run the
				program from a terminal and look at stdout.</li>
		</ul>
	</description>
	<screenshots>
		<screenshot type="default">
			<image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/blackhole89/notekit/master/screenshots/notekit-example.png</image>
		</screenshot>
	</screenshots>
	<url type="homepage">https://github.com/blackhole89/notekit</url>
	<content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

<!-- Add releases here in the future (and remove these comment tags)
	<releases>
	</releases>
-->
</component>
